export const Data = [
  {
    question:
      "Which HTML tag is used to define the structure of an HTML document?",
    option1: "<header>",
    option2: "<body>",
    option3: "<doctype>",
    option4: "<html>",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the correct HTML tag for inserting a line break?",
    option1: "<lb>",
    option2: "<br>",
    option3: "<break>",
    option4: "<newline>",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the HTML <meta> tag?",
    option1: "To define a list of meta keywords ",
    option2: "To define the character encoding of the document",
    option3: "To provide metadata about the HTML document",
    option4: "To create a metadata table",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the HTML <iframe> tag?",
    option1: "To create a clickable image",
    option2: "To embed another webpage within the current webpage",
    option3: "To define an image map",
    option4: "To display a video",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: `What does the "alt" attribute in an <img> tag provide?`,
    option1: "The image source URL",
    option2: "The image dimensions",
    option3: "A description of the image for accessibility",
    option4: "The image format",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the HTML <mark> tag?",
    option1: "To highlight text with a background color",
    option2: "To create a bookmark",
    option3: "To create a clickable link",
    option4: "To display mathematical equations",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the HTML <pre> tag?",
    option1: "To create a preview of an image",
    option2: "To create a presentation",
    option3: "To display preformatted text with spacing and line breaks",
    option4: "To define a prefix for text",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which HTML tag is used for defining a section of content that is related to the main content, but can be distributed independently?",
    option1: "<aside>",
    option2: "<article>",
    option3: "<section>",
    option4: "<div>",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the HTML <details> and <summary> elements?",
    option1: "To define the structure of a form",
    option2: "To create collapsible content sections with a summary",
    option3: "To display a progress bar",
    option4: "To insert a date and time",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "In HTML, what is the purpose of the <noscript> element?",
    option1: "To define a nested script block",
    option2: "To create invisible text",
    option3: "To specify a non-breaking space",
    option4:
      "To provide an alternative content for browsers that don't support scripts",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which HTML5 attribute allows an element to have multiple values separated by spaces?",
    option1: "multiple",
    option2: "multivalue",
    option3: "composite",
    option4: "multifield",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which HTML attribute is used to specify the relationship between the current document and a linked resource, such as a stylesheet or icon?",
    option1: "hreflang",
    option2: "rel",
    option3: "media",
    option4: "alt",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "Which HTML tag is used for defining a client-side image map?",
    option1: "<imagemap>",
    option2: "<map>",
    option3: "imagearea",
    option4: "<area>",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the HTML5 element used for grouping and styling together parts of the document's content for CSS purposes?",
    option1: "<group>",
    option2: "<stylegroup>",
    option3: "<divgroup>",
    option4: "<span>",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the HTML5 element used to define a container for navigation links within a document?",
    option1: "<nav>",
    option2: "<menu>",
    option3: "<links>",
    option4: "<navbar>",
    ans: 1,
  },
  {
    question: `What does the HTML <meta name="viewport"> tag do?`,
    option1: "Defines the character encoding of the document",
    option2: "Specifies the author's name for the page",
    option3: "Sets the title of the document",
    option4: "Controls the page's viewport properties for responsive design",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the HTML <output> element?",
    option1: "To define the output directory for files",
    option2: "To create a placeholder for external content",
    option3: "To display the result of a calculation or user action",
    option4: "To format text as code",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the HTML5 element used for grouping together a set of form elements and their labels?",
    option1: "<fieldgroup>",
    option2: "<group>",
    option3: "<labelgroup>",
    option4: "<feildset>",
    ans: 4,
  },
];
